Guide to the English Nationality Room Committee Collection, 1931-1981 UA.40.07
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Volume II: Bossom Correspondence, 1948-1963; II.
  - Correspondence, 1951; 4.
    - Telegram from Mitchell to Reginald Fairlie, July 16, 1951 (Item 38)
    - Telegram from Mitchell to Peter Heath, July 16, 1951 (Item 39)
    - Telegram from Mitchell to Margaret Godley, July 9, 1951 (Item 40)
    - Mitchell to Fitzgerald, July 16, 1951 (Item 41)
    - Mitchell to Fitzgerald, July 20, 1951 (Item 42)
    - Mitchell to Dorothy Leet, July 20, 1951 (Item 43)
    - Fitzgerald to Stanton Crawford, September 20, 1951 (Item 44)
    - Stanton Crawford to Fitzgerald, Spetember 19, 1951 (Item 45)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, November 30, 1951 (Item 46)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, March 5, 1951 (Item 47)
    - Note regarding Bossom, Fitzgerald and Klimcheck, November 27, 1951 (Item 48)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, November 30, 1951 (Item 49)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, December 12, 1951 (Item 50)
  - Correspondence, 1952; 5.
    - Bossom to Fitzgerald, February 18, 1952 (Item 1)
    - Copy of Personal note from Mitchell to Bossom, February 21, 1952 (Item 2)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, February 21, 1952 (Item 3)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, March 4, 1952 (Item 4)
    - Telegram from Bossom to Mitchell, February 28, 1952 (Item 5)
    - Telegram from Mitchell to Bossom, February 29, 1952 (Item 6)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, March 18, 1952 (Item 7)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, March 17, 1952 (Item 8)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, April 24, 1952 (Item 9)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, April 28, 1952 (Item 10)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, April 29, 1952 (Item 11)
    - Fitzgerald to Samuel Scharpiro & Company, Inc., April30, 1952 (Item 12)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, May 5, 1952 (Item 13)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, May 9, 1952 (Item 14)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, May 9, 1952 (Item 15)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, May 19, 1952 (Item 16)
    - Bossom to James Roberston, May 1952 (Item 17)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, May 21, 1952 (Item 18)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, June 19, 1952 (Item 19)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, July 7, 1952 (Item 20)
    - Telegram from Bossom to Mitchell, July 7, 1952 (Item 21)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, July 14, 1952 (Item 22)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, July 14, 1952 (Item 23)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, July 14, 1952 (Item 24)
    - Telegram from Bossom to Mitchell, July 18, 1952 (Item 25)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, July 23, 1952 (Item 26)
    - Fitzgerald to Bossom, July 28, 1952 (Item 27)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, July 28, 1952 (Item 28)
    - Bossom to Fitzgerald, August 9, 1952 (Item 29)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, August 9, 1952 (Item 30)
    - Mary Louise Woods to Bossom, August 12, 1952 (Item 31)
    - Telegram from Bossom to Fitzgerald, August 18, 1952 (Item 32)
    - M. Edgcumbe to Mitchell, August 22, 1952 (Item 33)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, August 25, 1952 (Item 34)
    - Bossom to Fitzgerald, September 5, 1952 (Item 35)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, September 12, 1952 (Item 36)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, September 15, 1952 (Item 37)
    - Tentative Draft of Program for the Dedication of the English Room (Item 38)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, September 12, 1952 (Item 39)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, September 16, 1952 (Item 40)
    - Bishop Brown to Bossom, September 16, 1952 (Item 41)
    - Fitzgerald to Bossom, September 17, 1952 (Item 42)
    - M. Edgcumbe to Mrs. Crawford Mitchell, Septmber 22, 1952 (Item 43)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, September 30, 1952 (Item 44)
    - Bossom to Fitzgerald, September 30, 1952 (Item 45)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, October 8, 1952 (Item 46)
    - Telegram from Mitchell to Castell's, October 7, 1952 (Item 47)
    - Hymns for Dedication Ceremony (Item 48)
    - Bossom to Fitzgerald, October 16, 1952 (Item 49)
    - Telegram from Fitzgerald to Bossom, October 21, 1952 (Item 50)
    - Telegram from Fitzgerald to Bossom, October 21, 1952 (Item 51)
    - Telegram from Bossom to Mitchell, October 21, 1952 (Item 52)
    - Telegram from Bossom to Mitchell, October 18, 1952 (Item 53)
    - Telephone Message from Howard Smith, October 22, 1952 (Item 54)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, October 23, 1952 (Item 55)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, October 27, 1952 (Item 56)
    - Telegram from Bossom to Mitchell, October 31, 1952 (Item 57)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, October 31, 1952 (Item 58)
    - Telegram from Mitchell to Bossom, November 6, 1952 (Item 59)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, November 7, 1952 (Item 60)
    - Stanton Crawford to Dr. John W. Oliver, Dr. Elmer Graper, and Professor Walter Hovey, November 7, 1952 (Item 61)
    - Telegram from Fitzgerald to Bossom, October 17, 1952 (Item 62)
    - Telegram from Bossom to Fitzgerald (Item 63)
    - Telegram from Fitzgerald to Bossom, November 25, 1952 (Item 64)
    - Telegram from Bossom to Mitchell, November 26, 1952 (Item 65)
    - Telegram from Bossom to Mitchell, November 17, 1952 (Item 66)
    - Telegram from Bossom to Mitchell (Item 67)
    - Telegram from Bossom to Mitchell, November 12, 1952 (Item 68)
    - Telegram from Bossom to Mitchell (Item 69)
    - Dotter to Bossom, November 26, 1952 (Item 70)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, November 26, 1952 (Item 71)
    - First Draft of a Suggestion for the Wording of the Bronze Tablet Commemorating the Gift of Materials from the House of Commons (Item 72)
    - Draft of the Commemorative Bronze Tablet for the English Room (Item 73)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, December 4, 1952 (Item 74)
    - Memo from Mitchell to Fitzgerald, December 16, 1952 (Item 75)
    - Jane Key to Mitchell, December 17, 1952 (Item 76)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, December 17, 1952 (Item 77)
    - Telegram from Bossom (Item 78)
    - Memo from Mitchell to Fitzgerald, December 2, 1952 (Item 79)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, December 2, 1952 (Item 80)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, December 12, 1952 (Item 81)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, December 23, 1952 (Item 82)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, December 29, 1952 (Item 83)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, December 29, 1952 (Item 84)
  - Correspondence, 1953; 6.
    - Cowell to Edgcumbe, January 5, 1953 (Item 1)
    - Edgcumbe to Mitchell, January 2, 1953 (Item 2)
    - Edgcumbe to Mitchell, January 2, 1953 (Item 3)
    - Cowell to Edgcumbe, January 9, 1953 (Item 4)
    - Goodale to Bossom, January 13, 1953 (Item 5)
    - Edgcumbe to Mitchell, January 19, 1953 (Item 6)
    - Warner & Sons Limited Receipt, January 13, 1953 (Item 7)
    - Goodale to Bossom, January 12, 1953 (Item 8)
    - Bossom to Goodale, January 8, 1953 (Item 9)
    - Edgcumbe to Cowell, January 15, 1953 (Item 10)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, January 19, 1953 (Item 11)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, January 19, 1953 (Item 12)
    - Telegram from Bossom to Mitchell, January 19, 1953 (Item 13)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, January 23, 1953 (Item 14)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, February 2, 1953 (Item 15)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, February 26, 1953 (Item 16)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, March 17, 1953 (Item 17)
    - Fitzgerald to Bossom, April 2, 1953 (Item 18)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, April 15, 1953 (Item 19)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, April 29, 1953 (Item 20)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, May 7, 1953 (Item 21)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, May 15, 1953 (Item 22)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, May 26, 1953 (Item 23)
    - P.H. Gore-Boothe to Jane Key, July 6, 1953 (Item 24)
    - Copy of Letter of Patent for Aldred Bossom awarded by Elizabeth II (Item 25)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, July 13, 1953 (Item 26)
    - Edgcumbe to Mitchell, August 28, 1953 (Item 27)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, September 30, 1953 (Item 28)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, September 30, 1953 (Item 29)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, October 6, 1953 (Item 30)
    - Bossom to Fitzgerald, November 3, 1953 (Item 31)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, December 16, 1953 (Item 32)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, November 21, 1953 (Item 33)
    - Wincester Cathedral Broderers pamphlet by L.F. Pesel (Item 34)
    - Photograph of embroidered cushion (Item 35)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, December 7, 1953 (Item 36)
    - Telegram from Mitchell to Bossom (Item 37)
    - Fitzgerald to Bossom, December 22, 1953 (Item 38)
  - Correspondence, 1954; 7.
    - Bossom to Mitchell, January 7, 1954 (Item 1)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, January 1954 (Item 2)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, January 13, 1954 (Item 3)
    - Who's Who 1953: Alfred Bossom entry, January 20, 1954 (Item 4)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, January 19, 1954 (Item 5)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, January 25, 1954 (Item 6)
    - Fitzgerald to Bossom, February 2, 1954 (Item 7)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, March 26, 1954 (Item 8)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, April 23, 1954 (Item 9)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, May 4, 1954 (Item 10)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, May 19, 1954 (Item 11)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, May 25, 1954 (Item 12)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, July 6, 1954 (Item 13)
    - Fitzgerald to Bossom, July 8, 1954 (Item 14)
    - Viers Adams to Gerald Firth, July 9, 1954 (Item 15)
    - Adams to William Milne Guthrie, July 9, 1954 (Item 16)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, July 14, 1954 (Item 17)
    - Bossoms to Mitchell, July 27, 1954 (Item 18)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, August 2, 1954 (Item 19)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, August 6, 1954 (Item 20)
    - Mary Newell to Mitchell, August 8, 1954 (Item 21)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, August 12, 1954 (Item 22)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, August 16, 1954 (Item 23)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, August 17, 1954 (Item 24)
    - Edgcumbe to Mitchell, August 19, 1954 (Item 25)
    - Edgcumbe to Mitchell, August 20, 1954 (Item 26)
    - Edgcumbe to Mitchell, August 23, 1954 (Item 27)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, October 18, 1954 (Item 28)
    - Telegram from Fitzgerald to Bossom, October 19, 1954 (Item 29)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, October 23, 1954 (Item 30)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, November 10, 1954 (Item 31)
    - Telegram from Mitchell to Bossom (Item 32)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, December 13, 1954 (Item 33)
  - Correspondence, 1955; 8.
    - Mitchell to Bossom, February 2, 1955 (Item 1)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, February 28, 1955 (Item 2)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, March 3, 1955 (Item 3)
    - Whistler to Bossom, March 27, 1955 (Item 4)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, March 8, 1955 (Item 5)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, March 9, 1955 (Item 6)
    - Master of Sinclair to Bossom, March 3, 1955 (Item 7)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, March 22, 1955 (Item 8)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, March 31, 1955 (Item 9)
    - Fitzgerald to Bossom, April 6, 1955 (Item 10)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, April 13, 1955 (Item 11)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, April 20, 1955 (Item 12)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, May 25, 1955 (Item 13)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, June 2, 1955 (Item 14)
    - Smolkovich to Bossom, June 29, 1955 (Item 15)
    - Dotter to Bossom, July 27, 1955 (Item 16)
    - Bossom to Dotter, August 8, 1955 (Item 17)
    - Dotter to Bossom, August 10, 1955 (Item 18)
    - Bossom to Dotter, August 22, 1955 (Item 19)
    - Bossom to Dotter, September 6, 1955 (Item 20)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, September 8, 1955 (Item 21)
    - Bossom to Elliot, September 23, 1955 (Item 22)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, October 27, 1955 (Item 23)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, October 19, 1955 (Item 24)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, November 24, 1955 (Item 25)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, November 5, 1955 (Item 26)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, December 1, 1955 (Item 27)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, December 13, 1955 (Item 28)
    - Instructions for Care of English Room Woodwork from Bossom, December 13, 1955 (Item 29)
    - Bossom to Mitchell (Copy), December 23, 1955 (Item 30)
  - Correspondence, 1956; 9.
    - Elliot to Richard Hadden, January 14, 1956 (Item 1)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, January 16, 1956 (Item 2)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, January 20, 1956 (Item 3)
    - Telegram from Bossom to Mitchell (Item 4)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, February 21, 1956 (Item 5)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, April 3, 1956 (Item 6)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, April, 1956 (Item 7)
    - Clive Bossom to Mitchell, April 20, 1956 (Item 8)
    - Schedule of Clive and Barbara Bossom's visit, May 8-10, 1956 (Item 9)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, June 4, 1956 (Item 10)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, May 17, 1956 (Item 11)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, May 22, 1956 (Item 12)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, June 4, 1956 (Item 13)
    - Clive Bossom to Mitchell, June 15, 1956 (Item 14)
    - Mitchell to Barbara Bossom, June 19, 1956 (Item 15)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, June 19, 1956 (Item 16)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, June 21, 1956 (Item 17)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, June 29, 1956 (Item 18)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, June 30, 1956 (Item 19)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, July 5, 1956 (Item 20)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, July 5, 1956 (Item 21)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, July 30, 1956 (Item 22)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, September 26, 1956 (Item 23)
    - Extracts from a Report from Charles Elliott after a Conference with Sir Alfred Bossom, September 24, 1956 (Item 24)
    - Mitchell to Richard Hadden, October 13, 1956 (Item 25)
    - Cook to Mitchell, October 12, 1956 (Item 26)
    - Firth to Bossom, December 21, 1956 (Item 27)
  - Correspondence, 1957; 10.
    - Mitchell to Bossom, January 11, 1957 (Item 1)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, February 4, 1957 (Item 2)
    - Oyen to Bossom, February 25, 1957 (Item 3)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, March 15, 1957 (Item 4)
    - Bossom to Oyen, March 18, 1957 (Item 5)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, July 15, 1957 (Item 6)
    - Elliott to Bossom, September 16, 1957 (Item 7)
    - Bossom to Elliott, October 17, 1957 (Item 8)
  - Correspondence, 1958; 11.
    - Elliott to Bossom, May 22, 1958 (Item 1)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, July 22, 1958 (Item 2)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, September 17, 1958 (Item 3)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, October 3, 1958 (Item 4)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, November 5, 1958 (Item 5)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, November 12, 1958 (Item 6)
    - Bossom's Secretary to Mitchell, November 14, 1958 (Item 7)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, December 12, 1958 (Item 8)
  - Correspondence, 1959; 12.
    - Bossom to Mitchell, February 4, 1959 (Item 1)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, February 23, 1959 (Item 2)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, February 28, 1959 (Item 3)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, May 20, 1959 (Item 4)
    - Mitchell to Bossom, May 18, 1959 (Item 5)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, June 19, 1959 (Item 6)
  - Correspondence, 1960; 13.
    - Bill Eldridge to Mitchell, March 23, 1960 (Item 1)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, April 16, 1960 (Item 2)
  - Correspondence, 1961; 14.
    - Mitchell to Bossom, June 20, 1961 (Item 1)
    - Bossom to Mitchell, July 11, 1961 (Item 2)
  - Christmas Cards from Bossom, 15.
    - Card, 1949 (Item 1)
    - Card, 1952 (Folder 2)
    - Card, 1953 (Item 3)
    - Card, 1954 (Item 4)
    - Card, 1955 (Item 5)
    - Card from Clive and Barbara Bossom, 1956 (Item 6)
    - Card, 1957 (Item 7)
    - Card, 1958 (Item 8)
    - Card, 1959 (Item 9)
    - Card, 1960 (Item 10)
    - Card, 1961 (Item 11)
    - Card, 1962 (Item 12)
- Volume III: Dedication 1952, Gifts 1948-1963, Clippings 1930-1961, III.
  This volume contains correspondence and programs concerning the 1952 dedication of the English Nationality Room. Also included is information about a variety of gifts to the room, including furniture, art work, and architectural elements, such as wood and stone from the House of Commons. Clippings from newspapers and other publications concerning the room are also present.
  - Dedication, 1952; 1.
    - Invitations to Press Preview and Room Dedication (Volume 3, Item 1)
    - Program (Item 2)
    - Speech by Mrs. Ruth Crawford Mitchell (Item 3)
    - Speech by Alfred Bossom (Item 4)
      - Typed Copy of Speech by Alfred Bossom, 1.
      - Original Copy of Bossom's Speech, 2.
    - Speech by Sir Christopher Steel (Item 5)
    - Texts of Presentation for Symbolic Gifts (Item 6)
      - King James Bible, 1.
      - Philosophiae Naturalis Principia Mathematica, 2.
      - Magna Carta, 3.
    - Arrangements (Item 7)
      - Memo from Mitchell to Fitzgerald, September 26, 1952; 1.
      - Memo from Adams to Fitzgerald, September 24, 1952; 2.
      - Memo from Mitchell to Fitzgerald, October 3, 1952; 3.
      - Sixth draft of program for dedication, October 17, 1952; 4.
      - Tentative Schedule, November 11, 1952; 5.
      - Publicity Report, November 11, 1952; 6.
      - Program draft, November 13, 1952; 7.
      - Schedule of Work, November 21-22, 1952; 8.
      - Music Booklet, 9.
      - Castel & Son Ltd. to Dotter, December 2, 1952; 10.
    - Press Releases (Item 8)
      - Memo to Mitchell, October 31, 1952; 1.
      - Biography of Alfred Bossom, 2.
      - Biography of Christopher Steel, 3.
      - Guests for the English Room dedication, 4.
      - General Information on the Nationality Rooms, 5.
    - Letters of Regret (Item 9)
      - Livingstone to Fitzgerald, November 12, 1952; 1.
      - Coville to Fitzgerald, October 12, 1952; 2.
      - Mitchell to Cooley, October 3, 1952; 3.
      - Morrison to Fitzgerald, November 11, 1952; 4.
      - D'Egville to Fitzgerald, November 13, 1952; 5.
    - Copy of Pitt Quarterly, Winter 1952-1953 (Item 10)
  - Gifts, 2.
    - List of Gifts to the English Room, 1956 (Item 1)
    - Portrait of a Lady booklet (Item 2)
    - Letter from Elizabeth Robins to Sam and Elsa, 1948 (Item 3)
    - Memorandum from Bowman, February 17, 1948 (Item 4)
    - Mitchell to Eliot, February 27, 1948 (Item 5)
    - Mitchell to Elizabeth Robins, 1948 (Item 6)
    - Transcript of Letter from William Wilberforce to Samuel Wilberforce, 1822 (Item 7)
    - Mitchell to Robins, September 21, 1950 (Item 8)
    - Bust of Willaim Pitt (Item 9)
      - Description, 1948; 1.
      - Mitchell to Doty, February 5, 1948; 2.
      - Memo from Doty to Mitchell, February 6, 1948; 3.
      - Mitchell to Godfrey, February 9, 1948; 4.
      - Godfrey to Mitchell, April 16, 1948; 5.
    - Wood and Stone from Blitzed House of Commons, 1949 (Item 10)
      - Clifton Brown to Fitzgerald, November 15, 1949; 1.
    - Nest of Tables (Item 11)
      - Text of Speeches on the Occasion of the Presentation, October 25, 1950; 1.
      - Mansbridge to Fitzgerald, April 21, 1950; 2.
      - Fitzgerald to Queen Mary, May 3, 1950; 3.
      - Wickham to Fitzgerald, May 12, 1950; 4.
      - Carter to Fitzgerald, June 2, 1950; 5.
      - Fitzgerald to Wickham, June 12, 1950; 6.
      - Fitzgerald to Carter, June 16, 1950; 7.
      - Transcript of Telephone Call between Carter and Fitzgerald, June 16, 1950; 8.
      - Fitzgerald to Carter, August 7, 1950; 9.
      - Carter to Fitzgerald, 1950; 10.
      - Carter to Mitchell, August 29, 1950; 11.
      - Mitchell to P.H. Gore-Booth, September 25, 1950; 12.
      - Carter to Mitchell, October 3, 1950; 13.
      - Mitchell to Carter, October 5, 1950; 14.
      - Draft of Statement for Presentation of Tables, 15.
      - Fitzgerald to Crawford, October 20, 1950; 16.
      - Guest List Suggestions, 17.
      - Suggested Program, 18.
      - Carter to Mitchell, October 26, 1950; 19.
      - Mitchell to Carter, November 1, 1950; 20.
      - J. Thurston to Mitchell, November 15, 1950; 21.
      - Fitzgerald to Queen Elizabeth the Queen Mother, November 20, 1950; 22.
      - Carter to Fitzgerald, December 6, 1950; 23.
      - Fitzgerald to Carter, December 19, 1950; 24.
    - Three Pictures of the House of Commons (Item 12)
      - Fitzgerld to Coote, May 11, 1951; 1.
      - Coote to Fitzgerald, May 23, 1951; 2.
    - Royal Coat of Arms of England (Item 13)
      - Crawley to Fitzgerald, October 1952; 1.
    - Gifts from Alfred Bossom (Item 14)
      - Bossom to Fitzgerald, February 22, 1952; 1.
      - Telegram from Bossom to Mitchell, February 28, 1952; 2.
      - Telegram from Mitchell to Bossom, February 29, 1952; 3.
      - Fitzgerald to Bossom, March 21, 1952; 4.
      - York to Fitzgerald, April 7, 1952; 5.
      - Key to York, April 23, 1952; 6.
      - York to Key, April 23, 1952; 7.
      - Fitzgerald to York, April 30, 1952; 8.
      - Memo from Key to Mitchell, May 13, 1952; 9.
      - Fitzgerald to Bossom, May 21, 1952; 10.
      - Boyd-Carpenter to Bossom, May 21, 1952; 11.
      - Bossom to Fitzgerald, November 12, 1952; 12.
      - List of Articles, 13.
      - Memo from Mitchell to Fitzgerald, December 16, 1952; 14.
      - Bossom to Mitchell, November 28, 1953; 15.
      - Bossom to Mitchell, February 19, 1954; 16.
    - Portrait of Andrew Mellon (Item 15)
      - Fitzgerald to Alisa Mellon Bruce, October 7, 1952; 1.
    - Portrait of the Earl of Chatham (William Pitt) (Item 16)
      - Article on William Pitt, 1.
      - Memo from Mitchell to Fitzgerald, March 24, 1952; 2.
      - Fitzgerald to O'Connor, May 29, 1952; 3.
      - Copy of the Portrait in Pitt Magazine, Summer 1949; 4.
      - O'Connor to Fitzgerald, June 11, 1952; 5.
      - Fitzgerald to O'Connor, June 12, 1952; 6.
      - Fitzgerald to O'Connor, October 1, 1952; 7.
    - Furniture, 1952 (Item 17)
      - Mitchell to Firth, January 7, 1952; 1.
      - Dotter to Firth, January 25, 1952; 2.
      - Memo from Mitchell to Fitzgerald, February 14, 1952; 3.
      - Mitchell to Firth, March 5, 1952; 4.
      - Firth to Fitzgerald, October 29, 1952; 5.
      - Fitzgerald to Mitchell, October 30, 1952; 6.
      - Fitzgerald to Firth, November 10, 1952; 7.
      - Photo of 1610 bulbous-leg side table, 8.
      - Photo of 1605 Credence table, 9.
      - Photo of 1570 Elizabethan chair, 10.
      - Photo of sideboard, 11.
      - Photo of cabinet, 12.
      - Photo of table, 13.
      - Garloch to Horton, December 16, 1952; 14.
    - Furniture, 1954 (Item 18)
      - Firth to Frick, July 19, 1954; 1.
      - Mitchell to Cooley, July 21, 1954; 2.
      - Rupp to Cooley, September 15, 1954; 3.
    - Two Oriental Rugs (Item 19)
      - Mitchell to Hunt, March 3, 1955; 1.
      - Mitchell to Fitzgerald, March 31, 1955; 2.
      - Fitzgerald to Hunt, April 5, 1955; 3.
    - Calendar of Ripon, England (Documents), 1961 (Item 20)
      - List of Ripon Documents, 1.
    - "Loving Cup," to commemorate the coronation of Her Majesty Queen Elizabeth II, June 2, 1953 (Item 21)
      - Certificate of authenticity of the Loving Cup, 1.
    - Grimsby Coat of Arms, 1963 (Item 22)
      - Letterhead of the Mayor of Grimsby, March 6, 1963; 1.
      - Pamphlet on the text of the Magna Carta, 1950; 2.
  - Clippings, 1930-1961; 3.
    - Family tree of English Royal Family, 1953 (Item 1)
    - Pittsburgh Record article, "English Gifts For English Room", October 1930 (Item 2)
    - Shenandoah Herald article, "Pittsburgh Receives London War Relics", December 31, 1948 (Item 3)
    - Pitt News article, "Hello, America! Merry old Brick Comes Across", Summer 1936 (Item 4)
    - Lake North, Florida article, "Gets Relics of Bombed Commons", December 31, 1948 (Item 5)
    - Scranton Post article, "Pittsburgh Gets Relics of Bombed Commons", January 9, 1949 (Item 6)
    - Pitt Quarterly article, "Nationality Rooms Christmas Party", Winter 1948-1949 (Item 7)
    - Pitt Quarterly article, "The English Room", Winter 1948-1949 (Item 8)
    - Pitt Quarterly article, "English", Spring 1950 (Item 9)
    - Pitt Quarterly article, "House of Commons", Winter 1949-1950 (Item 10)
    - Pitt Quarterly article, "The English Room", Spring 1951 (Item 11)
    - Pitt News article, "English Room Soon to Appear in Cathedral", December 1949 (Item 12)
    - Pttsburgh Sun-Telegraph article, "London Told of Pitt Room", July 18, 1951 (Item 13)
    - Daily Telegraph article, "English Room in Pittsburgh", November 1952 (Item 14)
    - Daily Telegraph article, "Thanks from Pittsburgh", July 1951 (Item 15)
    - Photo from Pittsburgh Press article, "The English Room, nearing completion, will be a bit of old England at Pitt", November 1951 (Item 16)
    - Photos from Pittsburgh Press article, "Stone and tile fireplace being installed" and "Bosses dating back to days of the Tudors", November 1951 (Item 17)
    - Pittsburgh Press article, "Pitt's Blitz-Born English Room", November 1951 (Item 18)